http://www.aem.org/privacy-and-cookies-policy/

×
This Website Uses Cookies
By using this website without changing the cookie settings
in your web browser you consent to all cookies in accordance
with the Cookie Policy.
Accept
About this Notice
This Privacy and Cookies Policy Notice ("Policy") provides you with information about how the Association of Equipment Manufacturers (hereafter "we", "us" or "our") collect, use, and disclose your data, and how to contact us in the event of a correction or complaint.
This policy also outlines how we collect, use and disclose certain personally identifiable information that we receive in the USA from the European Economic Area (“EEA Personal Data”), your rights in relation to your EEA Personal Data and how to contact us and EEA supervisory authorities in the event that you have a complaint.
Our websites (“Sites”) include: www.aem.org, shop.aem.org, www.agg1.org, www.agrievolution.com, www.conexpoconagg.com, www.worldofasphalt.com, www.ifpe.com, www.theutilityexpo.com, www.conexpolatinamerica.com, www.imakeamerica.com, and www.conexpoconnect.com.
Our “Services” include products, services, events, mobile apps, print and electronic information and communications to advance equipment manufacturers in the global marketplace. Our “Events” include in-person and virtual trade shows, meetings, conferences, seminars, committee meetings, board meetings, webinars, etc.
AEM members and member employees, exhibitors, participants and attendees at Events, visitors to our Sites, other users of our Services and Sites, and recipients of our communications agree to their personal information being used and disclosed in the manner set out in this Policy.
In the case of non-members and those who have not participated in our Events, we will obtain appropriate written permissions from you where necessary to use your information in accordance with this Policy, or where it is required and authorized by law.
This Policy only applies to our Sites and Services. If you land on other websites (or move to other websites from our Sites) you should read their separate privacy policies. Similarly, this Policy does not apply should you choose to share your personal information with an Event exhibitor or other Event participants either in-person or online.
Changes to this Policy
This policy was published on May 18, 2018, and updated on September 3, 2020.
We update this policy from time to time to reflect changes to our information practices. Please review this policy periodically for changes. If we make material changes, we will notify you by means of a notice on this website or in advance by email where required by law.
EEA Personal Data Collection and Use
Our Privacy Policy describes the categories of EEA Personal Data that we may receive in the USA as well as the purposes for which we use that EEA Personal Data. We will only process EEA Personal Data in ways that are compatible with the purpose that We collected it for, or for purposes the individual later authorizes. Before we use your EEA Personal Data for a purpose that is materially different than the purpose we collected it for or that you later authorized, we will provide you with the opportunity to opt out. We maintain reasonable procedures to help ensure that EEA Personal Data is reliable for its intended use, accurate, complete, and current.
If we collect sensitive EEA Personal Data, we will obtain your opt-in consent, including if we disclose your sensitive EEA Personal Data to third parties, or before we use your sensitive EEA Personal Data for a different purpose than we collected it for or than you later authorized.
Mobile message data collected from our Messaging Services are excluded from this policy and thus will not be shared with third parties.
What kinds of personal information do we collect and process?
We collect, store, and process certain personal information as follows:
Sites
When you use our Sites, as is the case with most websites, certain limited information (such as your browser type and IP or Internet Protocol address) will be collected automatically.
We use analytics tools on our Sites to provide products and Services you request, identify service issues to us, improve our Services, provide content tailored to your personal preferences, track the effectiveness of digital advertising, and to monitor traffic and usage of our Sites.
These tools may be provided by third-party service providers and may include the collection and tracking of certain data and information regarding the characteristics and activities of visitors to our Sites. We may disclose data, including personal information, to certain such third-party services providers in order to obtain such services. For details of those providers, please see “Who may receive my personal data?” below.
One of these providers is Google Analytics and more information about the ways in which they collect and process your personal data can be found here: (https://policies.google.com/privacy/partners).
Our Sites also use cookies (which includes third party cookies to support analytics functionality) and other similar technologies, such as web beacons.
We obtain your consent to the use of cookies when you first visit the site using a particular browser.
Cookies are small text files which are downloaded onto your device and collect information about the way in which you navigate and use websites and the internet. Cookies collect information which may allow us to identify you or your approximate location. The information provided by cookies helps us to provide you with a more personal experience, for instance by providing you with a local version of the Sites in a local language, and allows us to make improvements to our Sites and Services over time.
We collect both "session" cookies, which are not usually stored after your browsing session has ended, and "persistent" cookies, which may be stored after your session has ended.
You may delete and block all cookies or decide to just block certain types of cookies via your browser setting at any time. However, if you choose to block or delete cookies, this may affect the functionality of the Sites.
View the information below to learn about our cookie functions and why they are used.
Performance
These cookies collect information about how visitors use our Sites, including which pages visitors frequent most and if they receive error messages from certain pages. These cookies do not collect information that individually identifies a visitor. All information collected is aggregated and anonymous. It is only used to improve how our Sites function and perform.
An example of Performance cookies that we use on our website are:
Vendor
Description
AddThis
AddThis Platform gives website owners a platform in which to receive analytics on the usage of the AddThis Tools and the ability to customize the Tools. AddThis assigns a randomly generated ID to each web browser and provides aggregated browsing data to determine what content is being shared, what content is driving traffic to our site, and how users are sharing our content.
Google Analytics
Using Google Analytics cookies we are able to analyse user sessions on our website, such as traffic source, session duration, number of visits etc. Google Universal Analytics enables us to collect information about how visitors use our website, allowing us to make improvements where necessary.
Functionality
These cookies allow us to remember information you have entered or choices you make, (such as username, language or your region) and provide enhanced, more personalised features. These cookies can also be used to remember changes you have made to text size, fonts and other parts of web pages that you can customise.
We use local shared objects, also known as flash cookies, to store your preferences or display content based upon what you view on our Sites to personalise your visit.
Social Media (Features) and Widgets: Our sites include social media features, such as the Facebook Like button, LinkedIn follow button, and Twitter follow button. We also utilize the AddThis platform to provide users the ability to share our content on social media. These features may set a cookie to enable the feature to function properly. These features are provided by a third party, and your interactions with these features are governed by the privacy policy of the company providing it.
An example of Functionality cookies that we use on our website are:
Vendor
Description
AddThis
AddThis Tools are enabled on our website to allow users to instantly share our content to the most popular social media networks and other destinations via a website plug-in.
Kentico
Kentico, our Content Management System, sets cookies in order provide you with an optimal website experience. They remember your preferences and store the last page you visited, whether or not you're a new user, etc. for analytics purposes.
Targeted Advertising and Third Party Cookies
We use third parties to track and analyse usage and volume of statistical information. We sometimes use cookies delivered by third parties to track the performance of advertisements. For example, these cookies remember which browsers have visited our Sites. The information provided to third parties does not include personal information, but this information may be re-associated with personal information after we receive it.
We also contract with third party advertising networks that collect IP addresses and other information from web beacons (see below) on our Sites, from emails, and on third-party websites. Ad networks follow your online activities over time by collecting website navigational information through automated means, including through the use of cookies. They use this information to provide advertisements about products and services tailored to your interests. You may see these advertisements on other websites. This process also helps us manage and track the effectiveness of our marketing efforts.
Third parties, with whom we partner with to provide certain features on our website or to display advertising based upon your web browsing activity, use flash cookies to collect and store information. Flash cookies are different from browser cookies because of the amount of, type of, and how data is stored. To learn more about these and their opt-out instructions visit: https://policies.google.com/technologies/ads.
An example of Third Party cookies that we use on our website are:
Vendor
Description
Act-On
Tracks the activity of anonymous and known prospects (from our database) coming to the website. User is anonymous, but we do know the user's city/state/country.
Facebook
We use cookies to help measure the performance of ad campaigns.
Google Conversion Tracking
Utilized to track conversions from digital advertising. See: https://policies.google.com/technologies/ads.
LinkedIn
We utilize cookies to track whether or not a user who saw an ad later visited and took an action (e.g. completed a form or downloaded a white paper) on our site.
Hotjar
We use Hotjar in order to better understand our users’ needs and to optimize this service and experience. Hotjar is a technology service that helps us better understand our users’ experience (e.g. how much time they spend on which pages, which links they choose to click, what users do and don’t like, etc.) and this enables us to build and maintain our service with user feedback. Hotjar uses cookies and other technologies to collect data on our users’ behavior and their devices. This includes a device's IP address (processed during your session and stored in a de-identified form), device screen size, device type (unique device identifiers), browser information, geographic location (country only), and the preferred language used to display our website. Hotjar stores this information on our behalf in a pseudonymized user profile. Hotjar is contractually forbidden to sell any of the data collected on our behalf. For further details, please see the ‘about Hotjar’ section of Hotjar’s support site.
Messaging Services
We offer an SMS messaging service. You may choose to opt-in to our services by texting “JOIN” to 83797. You may opt-out at any time. We send links to our advocacy registration form and links to our grassroots advocacy campaigns to potential and current advocates who text a given code to a specified number.
Wireless carrier terms, conditions, message and data rates apply for messaging. Message frequency varies per user. You will only receive a message as a response to texting-in, you will not receive outbound messages. If you have any questions about your text plan or data plan, contact your wireless provider. To cancel your service, text “STOP” to 83797. We will respond with a single SMS message to confirm that you have been unsubscribed. After this, you will no longer receive SMS messages from us.
Text “HELP” to 83797 for a brief help message. When we receive a “HELP” message, we will provide instructions on how to use this service and how to unsubscribe. You may also contact AEM support at +1 (202) 898-9064 or email us at wbalkonis@aem.org.
Participating carriers include AT&T Boost Mobile, T-Mobile, Metro PCS, Verizon Wireless, Sprint, U.S. Cellular, Nextel, and Virgin Mobile. T-Mobile is not liable for delayed or undelivered messages.
Services
Similarly, in order for us to provide, improve, and communicate with you about our Services, we may collect and process personal information including name, address, telephone numbers, items purchased, payment details, email address, business and trade demographic information, title, job function, social media accounts, dietary preferences, apparel size, interests, activities/hobbies, age, gender, education, and lead retrieval, geographic location, images and videos of you at Events, and dwell time at Events, etc. Other information collected may include mobile app usage data, electronic device type, etc.
Member employees, exhibitors, and attendees submit personal information through forms, applications, or contracts for the purposes of membership, engaging in our Sites and Services, and receiving communications from us about our Sites and Services. Members, exhibitors, and attendees who submit personal information relating to other employees in their companies for the purposes of using our Services agree that they have the authority to do so and provide consent for current and future processing as outlined in this Policy.
For security purposes, exhibitors or attendees wishing to bring their children under 18 to an Event must register them and provide limited personal information in order for us to provide children with a name badge. Although our Sites and Services are not specifically meant for children, parents providing a child’s email and postal address consent to us communicating information to them about our Sites and Services.
If you wish to receive one of our email or newsletter communications, you will need to provide us with your name and email address. Where you have indicated you would like to receive newsletter(s) or other communications, we may send these together with marketing in the form of email alerts and bulletins to tell you about our Services.
What is the purpose of the processing?
We collect and process your personal information for the purposes of providing our Services and Sites, fulfilling our contractual obligations, and/or providing you with information and communications regarding our Services and Sites. We process the personal information we collect for a number of purposes:
Personalizing our current and future Sites and Services
To fit personal preferences which we have inferred from the information provided by you
To provide you with the appropriate local version of the Sites (see the "Analytics" and "Cookies" sections for more information)
Improving our current and future Sites and the Services
For example, you may be invited to complete our surveys and opinion polls. In completing a survey, you may provide us with personal information, including your name, email address, views, and opinions.
Communicating with you regarding current and future Sites and Services including through email, phone calls, postal mail, web advertising, etc.
Providing our current and future Services including:
Newsletters such as AEM Advisor, Advocacy Advisor, Ag Advisor, CONEXPO-CON/AGG 365, Exhibitor Alerts, etc.
Educational information (seminars, webinars and other educational offerings)
Technical, Safety & Regulatory information (safety standards, safety manuals, regulatory developments and compliance)
Global market intelligence data (statistics, market information) including industry surveys.
Advocacy (advocacy, public policy and legislation)
Online or in-person Events including trade shows, exhibitor and attendee services to support these Events, enhance the participant experience, and connect buyers and sellers.
Membership recruitment, engagement, and in-person or online networking.
Customer Service, Exhibitor Engagement and related support services.
Online commerce sites and in-person retail stores.
Where allowed, individuals who generate and post content on our Sites, including company or personal profiles, message board posts, chats, blogs, photos, etc. do so voluntarily. We will remove such personal information if requested and where required by law.
This Policy shall not apply to publicly available information on our Sites or elsewhere. Such publicly posted and available information shall not be considered personal data.
Who may receive my personal data?
In accordance with the terms of your Membership or Event participation or where you have specifically consented, we may disclose or share your personal information with third party service providers, Member companies, and Event participants/sponsors including:
The Association of Equipment Manufacturers' entities around the world;
Our joint venture partners that provide similar Services around the world;
Associations that co-own Events that we produce;
Associations that produce co-located Events;
Joint venture partners that co-own and produce Events on our behalf;
Our official Event vendors and service providers which support our production of these Services, including general contractors, AV providers, housing, transportation services, floral companies, electrical contractors, registration and lead retrieval providers, mobile app providers, official publisher, etc.
Law enforcement bodies, in order to comply with any legal obligation or court order and, where we are otherwise requested to provide information, we may provide it but only in accordance with applicable privacy and data protection laws; and
Other such similar organizations selected by us in order to provide the Services to you.
Third party service providers who process information to support our internal business operations including statistics data processors, email distribution, human resources, accounting, IT services, accounting, customer services, marketing, communications, PR, advertising, etc.
Previous, current or future Event participants may receive a list of Event attendees including your name, company name, and email address.
Member and Exhibitor company lists may be published on our Sites and may include contact information for the company’s designated contact.
Previous, current, or future Event exhibitors to mail you information through our authorized third party mailing vendor.
Third-Party Agents or Service Providers
We may transfer EEA Personal Data to our third-party agents or service providers who perform functions on our behalf as described in our this Policy.
We enter into written agreements with those third-party agents and service providers limiting their use of the data to the specified services provided on our behalf. We take reasonable and appropriate steps to ensure that third-party agents and service providers process EEA Personal Data in accordance with our obligations to you and to stop and remediate any unauthorized processing. Under certain circumstances, we may remain liable for the acts of our third-party agents or service providers who perform services on our behalf for their handling of EEA Personal Data that we transfer to them.
Third-Party Data Controllers
In some cases we may transfer EEA Personal Data to unaffiliated third-party data controllers. These third parties do not act as agents or service providers and are not performing functions on our behalf. We may transfer your EEA Personal Data to third-party data controllers for the purposes described in this Policy. We will only provide your EEA Personal Data to third-party data controllers where you have opted-in and we also limit their use of your EEA Personal Data so that it is consistent with any consent you have provided and with the notices you have received. If we transfer your EEA Personal Data to one of our affiliated entities, we will take steps to ensure that your EEA Personal Data is protected with the same level of protection that We provide. Where appropriate, information may be provided to these third parties, Member companies, and Event participants in an aggregated form, such that it would not personally identify you.
International Transfers
Our service providers may be located in the US or elsewhere in the world. Different privacy laws may apply in different countries, and you understand and unambiguously consent to the transfer of personal information to these countries, group companies and service providers. We only make these arrangements or transfers where we are satisfied that adequate levels of protection are in place to protect any information held in that country or that the service provider acts at all times in compliance with applicable privacy laws.
Where required under applicable laws we will take measures to ensure that personal information handled in other countries will receive at least the same level of protection as is given in your home country. For individuals in the EEA, transfers of personal data are subject to special rules under European data protection law. Whenever your personal data will be transferred outside the EEA (e.g. because you are based in the EEA and your data will be processed by us in the USA) we will inform you of this. In the event that your personal information is transferred to a foreign jurisdiction, it may be subject to the laws of that jurisdiction, and we may be required to disclose it to the courts, law enforcement agencies or governmental authorities in those jurisdictions but we will only do so where required by applicable laws.
Security
We have appropriate security measures in place to prevent personal information from being accidentally lost, or used or accessed in an unauthorized way. We limit access to your personal information to those who have a genuine business need to know it. Those processing your information will do so only in an authorized manner and are subject to a duty of confidentiality.
We also have procedures in place to deal with any suspected data security breach. We will notify you and any applicable regulator of a suspected data security breach where we are legally required to do so.
Disclosures for National Security or Law Enforcement
Under certain circumstances, we may be required to disclose your EEA Personal Data in response to valid requests by public authorities, including to meet national security or law enforcement requirements.
How long do we keep your information?
We keep records for as long as required to provide the relevant Services. If you have opted-in to receive communications from us, you will remain on our list until you notify us. We also keep records for our own legitimate interests, in accordance with legal requirements (4-10 years) and tax and accounting requirements (7 years to permanent). Rosters, meeting minutes, and other official association business documents are kept as a permanent record.
Where required by law, personal data in the following documents will removed after the following time periods:
Event registration list and other records of attendance: 3 years
Event Exhibitor Space Application & Contract: 10 years after completion of performance
Membership applications: 5 years after termination of membership
Canada’s Anti-Spam Legislation
We are committed in complying with Canada's Anti-Spam Legislation ("CASL"). CASL applies to any electronic communications sent by us to certain outside parties and is protected by a range of business procedures, processes and policies. CASL regulates all commercial electronic messages sent within, to, or from Canada (“CEM”), which are messages that include (inter alia) the encouragement of participation in a commercial activity.
In addition to this anti-spam communication, to show transparency of how your data will be handled, we have undertaken the following initiatives:
We have implemented CASL compliant consent forms.
Your consent is necessary in order for us to use your personal information to send a CEM. This consent typically must be “express”, but in certain circumstances can be “implied”. We have modified certain forms in order to ensure that your express consent is obtained. In addition, you can determine and manage your communication preferences by going to the Subscription Center from any CEM received from us, including having your email address removed from our mailing lists at any time. You may still receive electronic messages to the extent that they are exempt under CASL or implied consent has been given as set out below.
We may infer implied consent if:
We have an existing business relationship with you or had a business relationship with you which terminated less than two years ago;
We received an inquiry from you within the last 6 months;
You disclosed your contact details to one of our employees (for example you provided us with your business card or connected with us via social media).
We have modified our email footers.
Under CASL, all CEM must include certain prescribed content. For example, we must clearly identify ourselves as the party sending the CEM and provide a method whereby you can readily contact us.
We have incorporated "unsubscribe" mechanisms (explained below).
Some messages are specifically exempt from consent requirements. The following messages are exempt:
You have a personal relationship with one of our employees with whom you have previously had a direct, voluntary, two-way communication;
You have a family relationship with one of our employees who contacted you;
The CEM is sent to one of our affiliated companies;
The CEM was sent in response to your request or inquiry; or
The CEM was sent in order to enforce a legal right or obligation (for example, if you have an outstanding debt, or breached a contract that you have with us).
Your Rights
In some jurisdictions, you may have the right to request a copy of the personal information that We hold about you and to have it corrected where necessary.
You may also have a right, in certain circumstances, to have your personal data blocked or erased or request that we stop processing your personal information.
To exercise any of these rights, please email or write to us at the address provided below, and we will respond to your requests within all applicable timeframes. Please note that we may, where permitted under applicable law, charge an administrative fee and/or request proof of identity. We will respond to your requests within all applicable timeframes.
Under the General Data Protection Regulation, EEA residents have a number of important rights free of charge. In summary, those include rights to:
fair processing of information and transparency over how we use your use personal information
access to your personal information and to certain other supplementary information that this Policy is already designed to address
require us to correct any mistakes in your information which we hold
require the erasure of personal information concerning you in certain situations
receive the personal information concerning you which you have provided to us, in a structured, commonly used and machine-readable format and have the right to transmit those data to a third party in certain situations
object at any time to processing of personal information concerning you for direct marketing
object to decisions being taken by automated means which produce legal effects concerning you or similarly significantly affect you
object in certain other situations to our continued processing of your personal information
otherwise restrict our processing of your personal information in certain circumstances
claim compensation for damages caused by our breach of any data protection laws
If you would like to exercise any of those rights, please:
email or write to us;
let us have enough information to identify you;
let us have proof of your identity and address (a copy of your driving license or passport and a recent utility or credit card bill); and
let us know the information to which your request relates, including any account or reference numbers, if you have them.
EEA Access Rights
You may have the right to access the EEA Personal Data that we hold about you and to request that we correct, amend, or delete it if it is inaccurate or processed without a legitimate ground for such processing. These access rights may not apply in some cases, including where providing access is unreasonably burdensome or expensive under the circumstances or where it would violate the rights of someone other than the individual requesting access. If you would like to request access to, correction, amendment, or deletion of your EEA Personal Data, you can submit a written request to the contact information provided below. We may request specific information from you to confirm your identity. In some circumstances we may charge a reasonable fee for access to your information.
Whom can I contact?
If you have any questions about this Policy, would like to exercise your rights with respect to your personal information, believe we communicated with you in error, or have a complaint about how we handled your personal information, please contact:
Association of Equipment Manufacturers
Attn: Membership Department
6737 West Washington Street, Suite 2400
Milwaukee, WI 53214-5647 USA
By e-mail: datasecurity@aem.org
We hope that we can resolve any question or concern you raise about our use of your information. The General Data Protection Regulation also gives the right to lodge a complaint with a supervisory authority in the European Union (or European Economic Area) state where you work, normally live, or where any alleged infringement of data protection laws occurred.
Log In
Agriculture
Construction
Market Data
About
Safety & Technical
Trade Shows & Events
Advocacy
